[{"stepName": "Identify Motion of objects", "stepNumber": 1, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "How many moving objects are present?", "options": [1, 0, 3, 2], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": [""], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n"], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "How many strings are there?", "options": [2, 4, 3, 1], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}]}, {"stepName": "Write FBD equation for each Moving block", "stepNumber": 2, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block along the incline?", "options": ["+100sin(30\u00b0)+T\u2081=10a\u2081", "-100sin(30\u00b0)+T\u2081=10a\u2081", "+100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "-100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "+100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big blockyellow block and Big block", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 1 due to B?", "options": ["N1 perpendicular up", "N1 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "answer": 0, "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for red block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on red block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 down the incline ", "T\u2081 up the incline "], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block along the incline?", "options": ["+100sin(30\u00b0)+T\u2081=10a\u2081", "-100sin(30\u00b0)+T\u2081=10a\u2081", "+100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "-100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 100cos(30\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: T\u2081, ", "Forces down the incline: 100sin(30\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "-N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "+N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big blockyellow block and Big block", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "-N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 100cos(30\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: T\u2081, ", "Forces down the incline: 100sin(30\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block along the incline?", "options": ["+T\u2081+30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "+T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "-T\u2081+30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "-T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "+T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big blockyellow block and Big block", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 2 due to B?", "options": ["N2 perpendicular up", "N2 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "answer": 0, "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for yellow block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on yellow block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 up the incline ", "T\u2081 down the incline "], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block along the incline?", "options": ["+T\u2081+30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "+T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "-T\u2081+30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "-T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N2, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 30cos(60\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: T\u2081, ", "Forces down the incline: 30sin(60\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n", "+30cos(60\u00b0)+N\u2082=3a\u2082n", "-30cos(60\u00b0)+N\u2082=3a\u2082n", "-30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "+30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big blockyellow block and Big block", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n", "+30cos(60\u00b0)+N\u2082=3a\u2082n", "-30cos(60\u00b0)+N\u2082=3a\u2082n", "-30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N2, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 30cos(60\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: T\u2081, ", "Forces down the incline: 30sin(60\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "Yellow block: +30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n"]}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Equations", "stepNumber": 3, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2081+a\u2082p=0", "+a\u2081-a\u2082p=0", "-a\u2081+a\u2082p=0", "-a\u2081-a\u2082p=0"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "Yellow block: +30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "Yellow block: +30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n", "+a\u2081-a\u2082p=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["a\u2081: acceleration of red block in y-direction", "a\u2082p: acceleration of yellow block along the plane"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the number of parts which change length in the pink string?", "options": [5, 4, 2, 3], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "Yellow block: +30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "Yellow block: +30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n"], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 0}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for pink string due to red block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2081", "-a\u2081"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "Yellow block: +30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "Yellow block: +30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2082 for pink string due to yellow block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2082", "-a\u2082"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "Yellow block: +30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "Yellow block: +30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2081+a\u2082p=0", "+a\u2081-a\u2082p=0", "-a\u2081+a\u2082p=0", "-a\u2081-a\u2082p=0"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "Yellow block: +30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n"], "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant", "l\u2081'' = +a\u2081", "l\u2082'' = -a\u2082"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 0, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "Yellow block: +30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n", "Pink string: +a\u2081-a\u2082p=0"], "type": "advance"}]}, {"stepName": "Final Answers", "stepNumber": 4, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What are the final accelerations, tensions and normal reactions?", "options": ["a\u2081= 251.2, a\u2082p= -7.32, a\u2082n= -12.64, T\u2081= 5.5200000000000005, N\u2081= 59.6, N\u2082= 86.4", "a\u2081= -1.58, a\u2082p= -12.81, a\u2082n= 864.0, T\u2081= 89.4, N\u2081= 4.6000000000000005, N\u2082= 157.0", "a\u2081= -1.83, a\u2082p= 86.4, a\u2082n= 188.39999999999998, T\u2081= 104.3, N\u2081= 5.5200000000000005, N\u2082= -12.64", "a\u2081= -1.83, a\u2082p= 0.92, a\u2082n= -1.58, T\u2081= 31.4, N\u2081= 86.4, N\u2082= 14.9"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "finalanswer", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "Yellow block: +30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n", "Pink string: +a\u2081-a\u2082p=0"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": [], "tobeshown": 1, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082p, a\u2082n, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +100sin(30\u00b0)-T\u2081=10a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-100cos(30\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2081-30sin(60\u00b0)=3a\u2082p", "Yellow block: +30cos(60\u00b0)-N\u2082=3a\u2082n", "Pink string: +a\u2081-a\u2082p=0", "Final Answers: a\u2081= -1.83, a\u2082p= 0.92, a\u2082n= -1.58, T\u2081= 31.4, N\u2081= 86.4, N\u2082= 14.9"]}]}]